Okay, so in this video
then, we are going to
discuss some requirements
solicitation techniques.
Basically, some tools and techniques to
collect requirements.
Okay, now, let's think about this.
What is the most common way of collecting
requirements from your customer?
What's the most common way?
Sitting down with them and asking them
what they want, what they need.
That's the most common way, right?
That is known as interviewing.
And interviewing is a common tool we see
across the board.
It could be used for many, many processes,
interviewing.
Interviewing literally just means sitting
down with the stakeholder and asking them
what they want, what
they need, or asking them
questions, and then
documenting those questions.
That is interviewing.
And that's the most common
way then of collecting requirements,
asking the customer what
they want, what they need.
But there's other ways as well.
You might come across this term focus
group.
A focus group are a
group of stakeholders or a
group of pre-qualified
subject matter experts.
You're discussing a specific subject and
then you're trying to get their opinions.
That is what a focus group is,
right?
Getting a group of subject
matter experts or a group of
pre-qualified stakeholders
and getting their opinions.
So that's a difference between
interviewing and focus group.
An interviewing is generally
sitting down with an individual,
where the focus group is
getting opinions from pre-qualified,
pre-qualified subject
matter experts generally.
Now, another very
common tool of collecting
requirements is document analysis, right?
Now, document analysis is literally,
as it sounds, analyzing documents,
right, such as, for example, what are the
ISO standards, right?
Or what are the building codes?
What are the building regulations and the
building codes when we're building a house
or, you know, for you're doing a
construction project.
You're documenting, you're analyzing those
documents to determine the requirements,
in this case, a quality requirements for
this particular project.
Now that's a very simple example.
Plus you could be using historical data,
historical project files.
We've done this kind of project before.
What requirement, or you know,
a similar project, let me start again,
we've done a similar
project like this before,
what were the requirements
on the previous project?
So you're looking at all organizational
process asset, right?
Historical project files are known as an
OPA, an organizational process asset.
So there's another example of a document
analysis.
Also questionnaire and survey.
So you may be sending out a questionnaire
and survey with some high level questions
and the way the answer
those questions then
can determine all right, the next steps.
So it's a very simple example, back
in my HR days, for example, right?
When we would be
implementing, say, the defined
contribution 401K plans for
our Fortune 500 clients, right?
Then, you know, most of the time,
the project was almost identical.
They were very, very similar, right.
We would be installing, right,
we'd be implementing our platform.
We'd be implementing our system,
right, and the system was standard.
We would send out a standard
questionnaire, and, you know, there was
some, standard question, we just wanted to
get an idea of their current plan.
And then based on that now,
we can now drill down into some
more of the detail, some
more of the detail requirements.
But just to get some
high-level requirements,
we could send out
questionnaire and survey.
Now, another tool is benchmarking.
And benchmarking is comparing against a
standard.
That's what a benchmark is.
You're comparing against a standard,
whether it's an industry standard or a
company standard or a personal standard is
comparing against a standard.
So it's a very simple example.
What if I told you that I just purchased a
vehicle and it gives
me 18 miles per gallon?
Is that good or bad?
Well, some people immediately think, oh,
that's really bad, 80 miles per gallon.
And then some people will think, well,
hang on, what are we comparing it against?
I just said I purchased a vehicle and it
gives me 80 miles per gallon.
If this vehicle is a fully loading,
you know, 10-liter truck that's pulling a
two-ton weight and it
gives me, you know, 17,
18 miles per gallon,
that's probably not so bad.
Whereas if I purchase, you know,
a small vehicle and, you know,
typically the small vehicle Usually,
you know, competitors will give around 30
miles per gallon, 27 to 30 miles per
gallon.
And this one is only giving me 18 miles
per gallon.
That's not very good.
That's terrible.
So benchmarking is basically just that.
What we're benchmarking against,
what you're comparing it to.
So benchmarking means comparing against a
standard of some kind.
Other tools and techniques and for
eliciting requirements.
nominal group technique, right?
A nominal group technique is basically a
continuation of a brainstorming session.
Now, in a brainstorming session,
the whole idea of a brainstorming session
is to try and get as many ideas as
possible.
In a brainstorming, you do not discuss
those ideas.
You do not judge anyone's ideas.
You try to get as many ideas as possible.
It's a nominal group technique where now
You discuss those ideas, you vote,
and then you rank those ideas.
And ideally, it could be done by another
team, by a separate team, free from bias.
It doesn't have to be, though.
It doesn't have to be a separate team.
But oftentimes it is,
you know, because free
from bias or one team
comes up with the ideas.
Another team discusses, rank votes and
ranks those ideas.
Another tool is observation.
Observation, actually observing.
I mean, literal as it sounds, observing
the process.
job shadowing, for example, especially the
case if it's a process
improvement project.
We want to see what the current procedures
are.
What's the current process?
If you don't know what the current process
is, what are you going to improve?
So you need to observe.
Another tool is this one called
facilitation or facilitated workshops.
And this really is bringing
cross-functional stakeholders together,
right, to come up with a solution.
and in this case to come up with some
requirements.
Now, there's two
specific types of facilitated
workshops that PMI have
mentioned in PNBOC.
You don't need to know them in any amount
of detail, but just because of mentioned
it in PIMBOC, that's why we wanted to just
mention it here as well.
And the reason why you
won't get any detailed questions
because these are both
really industry-specific.
One is called Joint Application
Development, or Jad.
and that is specifically for software,
software projects.
And then another one
called QFD, quality function
deployment, generally
in manufacturing industry.
And that is used to capture voice of the
customer.
And the whole principle behind both of
these is to try and capture a good set of
requirements in the shortest possible
time.
In agile, in the agile environment, those
requirements are known as user stories.
Now, other tools, you might be able to be.
might come across this term called the
voting method.
And a voting method, basically,
there's four basic types.
Unanimous, majority, plurality,
autocratic.
It's a unanimous where everybody agrees.
So we have, say, a couple of
possibilities.
Let's say we've got two
possible requirements,
but our budget only
allows for one of them.
So we put it to the vote, right,
to the senior stakeholders.
It could be a unanimous decision where
everybody agrees.
Or it could be a majority right,
51%, right, greater than 50%, right?
That's the one that we're going to go
with.
Or it could be a plurality
where we have the
largest percentage or
the largest voting block.
We might not necessarily get a 51%
majority.
So for example, let's say there's four
possible requirements.
We have to choose two of them.
Well, we're never going
to get a majority and we're
not, we're never going to
get unanimous necessarily.
Right.
So we'll go with a plurality.
Or it could be autocratic where one person
makes a decision for everyone.
And that could be something that's
predetermined.
I mean, you think, well,
autocratic, one person making
a decision for everyone,
how is that voting method?
Well, it still can be.
If it's decided beforehand, if it's
decided that if we cannot come to a
decision, if we as a group
cannot make a decision,
then this person is going
to make a decision for us.
Right.
Then another tool is this one called the
multi-cryteria decision analysis,
a multi-critory decision-making.
What that means is that there are many
factors used to make a decision.
Then just some other minor tools as well
that, you know, PMI have just mentioned,
they've mentioned in PIMBOC, context
diagram.
A context diagram really is nothing more
than a flow chart.
Right, is this a flow chart showing
interactions between systems, processes,
and people?
Generally, you're not
asked to interpret a flow
chart most of the time
on the PMP exam, right?
But it's just showing, you
know, the systems and processes
and people and how they
all interact with one another.
I mean, which is a flowchart.
A prototype is a standard working model,
right, a mock-up, right?
So that can be used as a starting point
for collecting requirements.
Right?
So as a simple example, you want to create
a model.
a website, right, for your organization.
So, you know, you reach out to a vendor.
They can explain all they want,
right, about the different websites,
but until you actually see a template,
you know, really not going to understand
what kind of requirements
you want, how you
want the website to
look and so and so forth.
Let's say you have no idea about, you know,
web development or anything like that.
So you have a little mock-up, and then
based on that, now you can start seeing or
I'd like to put this image
here and this kind of image
there and this color here
and so on and so forth.
So that can start triggering thoughts
about requirements.
Another tool is this one called
storyboarding, which is just showing
visuals and images, right, process over a
process or an outcome.
Mind mapping, again, another type of flow
chart, right?
And it's just consolidating ideas together
and showing the
similarities and differences.
And then something called in an affinity
diagram.
An affinity diagram is just grouping
similar ideas together.
That's really an affinity diagram.
There's grouping similar ideas together.
So, for example, in an agile world,
when we're talking about user stories,
right, you've got small
user stories, large
user stories, medium-sized user stories.
Well, these are the
grouping of the small ones,
these are the medium ones,
these are the large ones.
You're just grouping basically similar
ideas together.
So that would be, you would use an
affinity diagram for it.
So these are just some of the common tools
for collecting requirements and the ones
that really you need to know about for the
PMP.